# Stepan Popov Frontend developer

Remote full-time job. Current location: Batumi, Georgia.

@StepanBim

stepan.popov.dev@gmail.com



(in) linkedin.com/in/popov-stepan



stepan-popov.dev

github.com/Bimimot

## Summary

I've been working efficiently in telecom companies in various positions for 15 years. When I was satisfied my management job less I decided to change my profession. Programming always attracted me as a field of unlimited opportunities for self-development. In 2019-2020 I was studying at Yandex School of Data Analysis. After successful passing of the graduation project I started working as a programmer. My self-organization skills and perseverance to goals have helped me become a part of the professional IT-team.

#### Professional skills

#### **Programming Languages**

### Frameworks/Libraries

#### Tools

**Testing** 

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS/SCSS

React, React Hooks, Redux, i18n, Express.js

Git, Webpack, Nginx, Postman, Figma Jest, Cypress

# Plan B Media (St.-Petersburg, Russia)

Web developer Full-time & remote 12/2020 - present

#### Work experience

- Designed front-end for SPA (investor's tool):
- configured nested routing (react-router-dom),
- implemented Redux and improved state management.

developed sets of reusability React-components,

Was in on MPA development (social network):

- initiated and realized migration from Javascript to Typescript, reduced development and debugging time.
- configured Webpack with hbs templates, TS, react, SCSS (webpack plugins),
- migrated the project from Webpack4 to Webpack5, optimized production bundle.
- implemented localization with custom configuration (react-i18next, i18next),
- devised post editor with media content (React, Draft.js).

- made responsible layouts (CSS/SCSS,BEM, Flexbox),
- implemented asynchronous processes using backend API (fetch, promises),
- developed forms with validation (React, RegExp),
- developed HBS templates (Handlebars),
- used GutLab for control workflow.

## Committee of the IT of Murmansk region

Head of the E-goverment Department 04/2013 - 10/2020

Team size: 8 persons.

Ensured the successful implementation and development of information systems, reduced the cost of using information systems.

JSC Rostelecom, Murmansk branch

Head of the B2B Department 07/2011 - 07/2012

Team size: about 50 persons. Ensured the implementation of major projects and compliance with deadlines,

increased the B2B customer base.

JSC Polarcom, (Murmansk, Russia)

Customer Service Specialist, Head of B2B Department 07/2004 - 04/2011

Team size: 5 persons.

Organized the workflow of the department, increased the B2B customer base by more than 2 times.

#### **Projects**

#### divplan.com/app#

#### bimimot.github.io/burger

bimimot.github.io/news-finder

HTML/HBS, JS, React, Redux, SCSS.

React, Redux, Websocket, DnD, JEST, Cypress

JS, HTML, CSS, Rest API, Express, Mongo

#### Qualifications

Yandex School of Data Analysis, 09/2021 - 12/2021 Yandex School of Data Analysis, 10/2019 - 10/2020 React Developer professional training course Web Developer professional training course

# The Bonch-Bruevich St-Petersburg University of

# Telecommunications, 1998 - 2004

## Education **Design Engineer**

Faculty of Telecommunication Technology and Biomedical Technical Devices

#### Languages

English: Intermediate. Russian: native